JAMIE SHERRIFF

PERSONAL PROFILE

I am working full time in the software industry as a software engineer after completing a Bachelor of Science Degree with a double major in Computer Science and Geography from the University of Canterbury. During my time at university I worked part time as an Intern QA engineer. Previously as a qualified electrical technician, I worked in the electronics industry for two years holding positions of production technician and team leader.

PERSONAL SKILLS AND ATTRIBUTES

- Able to work successfully as a member of a team.
- Ability to stay focused and reliable in a high pressure time constrained environment.
- Patient and a willingness to listen and learn.
- Determination to get the job done with a focus on quality.
- Always maintained a highly punctual and organised ethic throughout work and education.
- Good academic record with excellence awards in electronics.
- Acquired valuable people skills while working with a wide range of peers at work and during my education.
- Able to strive and achieve goals.

TECHNICAL SKILLS AND ABILITIES

- Experienced using programming languages Python, Java, C, C# and web languages including PHP, JavaScript (frontend JS and backend with Node.JS) and databases with SQL.
- Knowledgeable of Automation tools Selenium, Appium, Xcode Instruments, Android UI Automator and continuous integration software TeamCity and Jenkins.
- Development skills including Angular JS, native Android and the multiplatform mobile framework Appelerator titanium. Node.JS experience with packages including express, lodash, grunt and moment.
- Understanding of test suites and applications using Microsoft's .Net framework with Visual Studio
- Developed and tested RESTful web services with Node.JS, Python and .Net
- Familiar with version control systems Mercurial, Git.
- Confident using test frameworks Mocha, pytest and load testing tools Locust and Jmeter.
- Skilled with the use of computers and electronic equipment. Computer systems experience covers Microsoft, Linux, OSX, iOS and Android.
- Proficient using ESRI's Arc GIS and have used QGIS.
- Capable of using spatial analysis software GeoDA, CrimeStat, PySAL and Exelis's ENVI for imagery.
- Have built many computer hardware systems and often install operating systems, patches, applications, firewalls and home networks.
- Have my own electronic workbench setup at home for conducting computing and electronic repair work.
 I also run my own web server and network at home.
- Found online at: https://github.com/jamie-sherriff and https://bitbucket.org/jamiesherriff

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

November 2015 - Current: Intermediate Test Automation Engineer at Telogis A Verizon Company

- Automated entire testing regression suites by extending development on my previously established test frameworks. This included scaling mobile automation across multiple host machines and mobile devices.
- Improved test framework reporting to peers and managers while training developers to use and maintain established automation suites.
- Took on more development responsibilities including assisting with feature planning, bug fixing, build management and scrum participation.

November 2014 – November 2015: Junior Test Automation Engineer at Telogis.

- Involved in the design, architecting, developing and running of software systems and tools to ensure a high quality of software was met. One system I designed and constructed was to execute automation test suites on company mobile apps on both Android and iOS platforms.
- Developed web browser automation suites and continued maintaining existing Python test suites established during Intern program.
- Led the testing of new products and establishment of test suites

August 2012 - November 2014: Intern QA engineer at Telogis

- Straightforward intern tasks such as manual testing and updating of test procedures. The role evolved to
 include test planning and execution, test progress reporting, improvement of testing processes and test
 environment and maintenance.
- Investigated alternative mobile automation frameworks and established a UI automation test suite for company mobile applications on Android. Also completed other automation projects using Python to automate the testing of mobile web services.
- Successfully resolved difficult customer technical issues.

February 2011 - February 2012: : Production Technician and Team Leader at Enatel

Led a team to produce electrical systems which included staff management, quality control, software testing, creating testing standards and liaising with engineers and management. I was also still involved in production repairs, fault recording and reporting, root cause analysis and staff training.

2010 - February 2011: Test Technician at Enatel

• Tested power supply systems while being required to meet tight time deadlines and maintain high quality testing procedures. I was also trained to carry out quality assurance on products before shipping.

QUALIFICATIONS

2014:

• "Rapid Software Testing" course with testing professional James Bach.

2012-2014: University of Canterbury

- Bachelor of Science in Computer Science and Geography with a B+ grade average over the duration of my degree. Maintained an A Grade average in my last year of study.
- My Geography major was focused on GIS courses and gained experience with commercial GIS software.
 This also included environmental processes and gained knowledge of geospatial and geographic analysis.
- Computer Science covered a wide range of subjects including programming, software engineering, databases, networking, Internet technology, computer and operating systems, human interaction with software, and web architecture.

2009: Electec College of Technology

 Achieved the Electec College Certificate in Applied Electronics Technology with Distinction. Also achieved EST-A (Electrical Service Technician) qualification with a passmark of 95% and received a Top Achiever certificate from the EWRB.

2004–2008: Riccarton High School, Christchurch

Achieved NCEA level 3 with Excellence awards for level 3 Geography and Electronics.

INTERESTS

- IEEE member since 2012
- Enjoy running, biking and photography.
- Interested in computing, multimedia and electronics, and am always looking at new technology and its application to real world problems.
- Appreciate a good days fishing, hunting and four wheel driving.